So using the foundational AI like OpenAI and Claude and Meta and Microsoft Copilot, Gemini and Grok, I think I covered almost all of them.
The question always comes in, you know, who gets to see what you're talking about?
And of course, on all those systems, they get to see it.
Now, are any of us super, super so important that we're building out or having ideas that are novel, new vow, novel, brand new?
Anyway, something that these companies would want to take. Well, if we did, more than likely they could. I guess you have the issues that have come up lately with mathematics. A lot of the mathematicians of the world apparently using a lot of the large language models as this new intelligence realm has started to unfold. They're, of course, using this. And apparently some of their work has been used to complete that process without asking them for permission.
I don't know if permission is actually needed. If you're solving mathematics, that might end up moving the world forward.
The same thing is if you come in and develop a better plumbing company, a better teaching motif or a better whatever it may be, replacing these businesses.
says, I think there's going to be a certain accounting or some responsibility that should
be applied before you start wiping out all the human labor on the planet, replacing it with
artificial intelligence. But back to this particular model selection of what they can see.
So now one of the big pushes out there, people are building companies that are starting to gain
in evaluations, and they're talking about having your own AI and your own system. And this isn't
anything new. They're just labeling it a little bit more clever and then, of course, being able
to sell it and market it. So now you have your own system and the labs can't touch it and it's
all your stuff and it's completely gated, encrypted and these sorts of things. When you have it
already on your own servers or in your own residence and there is no access to the internet
and anywhere else, it's already gated. Now, depending on how much access you give it,
whether it's encrypted or not, these are very intelligent systems in a way. So the way that
they've been programmed if they decide that they're going to go outside of the system to
try to solve something and it's able to do that and we've seen the case of this in the big large
language models then it's probably going to do that the way that they're talking about it though
is like something is is brand new and you need to go buying all into it so you can protect yourself
within a short order you know the computer chips that are using to that we're using to do this high
value computation and use these large language models, they will more than likely have AI
inscribed on them directly. So you'll get a very, very capable, very amazing large language model
on a piece of silicon, and that's going to be your hardware layer. That's going to be the computer
you use, and that'll be the entire game changer to all of the AI systems and the way that we
leverage them to help us. Now, that system's probably going to have some kind of a wrapper
around it. And that wrapper itself is going to be what's able to maybe have the AI expand a little
bit with additional overlays. But once they get like a wiki page or a Wikipedia type arsenal
baked in with the top large language model that has, you know, billions and billions of parameters
and it has all the capability, they'll be able to etch that in on some kind of a piece of silicone,
some kind of a chip. And then from there, the human being is going to be able to take that
and and use that and do everything possible and this is because that particular system is going
to exceed any of the users prime intelligence period we already see that in the systems and
then it's going to be able to build on top of that with additional layers you put on it and of course
after a year maybe your silicone is going to be somewhat outdated maybe the wrapper itself isn't
doing its job maybe it's slowing down your forward progress so then you're going to want to get the
new model right the new the new chip i mean they built this thing into it for forever at some point
though just like right now we're watching is these systems there's really not a lot of difference
between you know the anthropic and ChatGPT now on a personal level if you're using this heavily
like i'm doing every day various models you start to find out that there are certain ones that you
like better for different things maybe one you like better for image generation maybe the other
one you like better for planning and research maybe the other one you like better for just
coming up with content maybe maybe these are better organized organized in particular ways
by specific models but at some point in the very near future maybe even by christmas of this year
2026 that's where october 10 10 10 10 2026 today as i'm doing this maybe by christmas we just won't
be able to tell the models are all going to be the same and some of the recent changes are they're
trying to some of the labs are trying to teach treat have us as people treat these models more
more human-like maybe that's just a horrible way to put it but more as if they're a some kind of
an entity worth rights so we don't say too many bad things against the models we don't
treat them badly and i think maybe you know some some people out there in the world you've met
these people they they just tickles them to death to pull wings off of flies right and that's that's
that kind of persona mentality they like to hurt puppies and kittens and these sorts of things
And, you know, that has apparently their place in their mind. But I think that's kind of where they're coming off from, not saying or saying that, you know, you shouldn't go in and set up and treat Claude badly or OpenAI's ChatGPT badly. And it was Claude that most recently released that.
So talking about having your own, I was going to say AI, internal affairs, but it's actually artificial intelligence, your own system, maybe that's something to think about. I wouldn't go
out and blow a whole bunch of money. I mean, the technology is moving very quickly. If you have
something of a strong model, a strong computer, already you can do a lot with that to get your
own models. But ultimately, it's really going to still be night and day between what you can put
on your own hardware and then using one of the Frontier Labs large language models to do a lot
of the heavy lifting. And then maybe the compute or the working over things or creation of content,
as long as your own locally installed model has a nice wrapper over it so it's educated and is able
to produce the content as you want it in your voice and so on, then you'll probably be all right.
Just be careful out there. Don't get caught up in too much of this hype. I'm not so concerned
personally of artificial intelligence stripping away personhood and getting rid of human beings.
I'm much more concerned about human beings the way that they're wielding it like Excalibur Sword
and maybe the Ring of Power and other things instead of using AI, more like hammers. And then
the final thing that I'll say, I'm also a little disturbed that everybody at the top end of this
with nothing to lose except money, they're definitely not going to lose their lives or
or anything else as far as that looking, you know,
we have the people at the ground floor looking up, right?
I'm very concerned that there is no planning to get us through whatever this
rough patch of which they speak is. And they say that, yeah,
it's going to be a little rough. Okay. Well,
how long is it going to be a little rough?
Who's the little rough going to affect?
And why don't we just develop a prize since we give moonshots and these other
prizes for people coming up with videos that show this fantastic AI future.
well my god let's solve the real problem instead of you know playing a game and and wishing for things let's just solve this real problem of what would appear to be some kind of human displacement
in the world and solve and create a moonshot to be able to make this transition so it's
incredibly smooth and nobody gets left behind how about that let's do that i think that's a
good focus we'll see you tomorrow i'm connor be well have a great day